My first app, it's called Glam Up. We
got a million users in the first six
months of launching. I think at peak we
were at around 150k MR. Sprout, I was
growing it for the first 8 months and we
did 250k MR. When I was handling all of
the UGC's, we were doing 100 million
monthly views.
>> That's Nicole. She built four apps
before turning 25 and the last two apps
did over 400 grand a month between them.
Now, the interesting part about Nicole
is that she started GlamUp out of her
bedroom while she was still in school
without any engineering background. So,
in this video, I'm going to sit down
with her to figure out the exact
playbooks she used to blow up four
different apps and what she'd do
differently if she was starting from
zero today. This is the Super Wall
podcast. I'm Joseph Choy, founder of
Consumer Club, a Discord where top
consumer app founders trade alpha and
what's working now in growth. I've been
talking to members doing a million ARR,
and they tell me they've been using
these two tools. Superwall has this free
AI tool trained on 422 profitable
paywall experiments across thousands of
successful apps. You upload a screenshot
of your payw wall and it gives you an
experiment idea to make more revenue
with the same number of users at
paywallexperiments.com. And if your
app's doing at least 100K MR, we host
vetted dinners in SF and New York to
hang out and network with other top app
founders. You can apply with the type
form in the description. Also, these app
founders have been telling me they use
ROR. I met Daniel, the founder of Ror,
at a dinner, and I got genuinely really
excited when he told me about Ror Max,
which is out now and has honestly
changed the game for coding mobile apps.
It's AI that oneshots full native iOS
apps with Swift code, camera, sensors,
haptics, payments, the whole stack. And
as you vibe code with ROR, you can
install prototypes directly onto your
iPhone with one click and then publish
to the App Store in two clicks. If
you've been waiting for AI coding that
actually does native iOS apps, well,
this is it. I got you guys a discount.
You can use the code superwall or use
the link below. Okay, I'm going to start
with these tweets. Um, you've been
putting out some crazy tweets with
flexing your MR and your users and uh
your views on TikTok and everything. It
seems like you have multiple apps. So, I
want to dig into some of the apps you're
building the playbooks and then I think
it's also pretty wild that you're you're
a senior in college, right? And you're
writing your you like wrote this report
on how you built these companies, which
is also like kind of crazy. So, yeah.
So, what's going on? What what are your
apps?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So, I've been building
apps for the past two years. I have four
apps right now. Um, my first two apps, I
built them in college, hence why I wrote
my senior college thesis on it. Uh, but
my first app, it's called Glam Up. We
got a million users in the first 6
months of launching. Um, I think at peak
we were at around 150K MR. It's a glowup
app for for women and makeup and
skincare, all that stuff. My second app
is called Prep AI. Uh we renamed it to
Sprout now, but it's basically Tinder
for jobs. So you can download the app,
upload your resume, and whenever you
swipe right on a job, we just
automatically apply for you with a
tailored resume and cover letter. Yes,
we also have a web app now. Uh but I'm
currently stepping down as an adviser
for them while working on the new apps
uh that are currently in stealth.
>> So you have four apps total and then
GlamUp and Sprout. you know, with
GlamUp, you've scaled to, you know, 150K
MR million users. Um, is this the one
that you're going to uh share the most
about? Cuz it seems like you really got
very specific into all the details in
the playbook of how you how you built
and grew this.
>> The good part about this is that
whatever I did for Glamob, I basically
did it, but but did it better for
Sprout. Um, and I have the most info on
GlMA because that's when I was in
college. I was like preparing for my 01.
So I I was like gathering a lot of
evidences for it. Uh, so that's why I
have the most resources there. But
basically everything is the same when it
comes to GlamUp and Sprout. I would say
Sprout is a bit more matured, you know,
when it comes to a lot of the systems
that we're building. But Glam Up is kind
of the version one of like uh what we
have now
>> cuz I think GlamUp is like a it's a
really good case study story for like
people that are either starting out with
their first app cuz you know similar to
how it was your first app, but also just
all the growth hacks and some of the
referral mechanisms and like a lot of
the you just had a I have a lot of
interesting I read through this and
there there's a lot of interesting stuff
that I want to just to start out like
what what was the app idea and like what
what does it do? the app idea. We were
loosely inspired by UMAX because my
co-founder Aaron um for for Glam, he was
in HFZ with uh some founders uh working
on consumer apps. Um was one of it and
we just decided to build something, you
know, kind of in that space, but it's a
glowup app before women and makeup or
for guys and makeup. Um, and we were
like 2 years ago. It wasn't like that
big of a thing, you know, when it comes
to AI consumer apps yet. Um, not not
that many like vibe coders coming in at
that point. So, we just went on app
store. Uh, we didn't really find that
many apps doing that. Um, and we just
decided to make one. And it was funny.
It was um my co-founder for for Glam,
Aaron, he just called me. Uh, we just
had a 10-minute conversation. And in
that 10 minutes, we decided to start an
app together. We decided on the app name
and the app concept and how it's going
to work and that became Glam Up.
>> In your article, you said it was it was
like a copycat app, right? Is this your
is this your like what you're referring
to or is this different one?
>> No, no, no. So, this is interesting. We
were growing Glamob and then we got kind
of exposed on Twitter. So, so some
people started posting about Glamob and
how how much money it's making and this
and that. and someone copied our app,
but it was a brand new app and they
weren't ranking on on App Store and they
chose a very similar name. So, when they
started going viral, all the all the
traffic went to us. So, like I see and
then they just made us, you know, 100k
in a week.
>> Okay. So, that was like a crazy ASO
thing. We'll we'll get into that a
little bit later. But is it is this the
the page for the app?
>> Yes, this is the page for the app. Um,
as you can see, we haven't worked on it
for a year now.
>> This So, this is your first ever app
with your co-founder. Like, how long did
it take to build it?
>> Um, let me think. I think we built the
first MVP out in maybe 3 weeks to a
month. Like that. That was like our both
of our first time building an app. So,
it took us a bit longer. It was all
brown. The app barely worked. And it was
just a concept. like it was genuinely an
MVP that we just launched, but we didn't
really care, you know, we were working
on distribution at the same time and uh
Glam Up like the current pink version is
our version two and this one took us
maybe a month to really improve and and
optimize.
>> So, you mentioned UMAX like um I think
some people know about it, but for
people who don't, like how did you come
to the idea for GlamUp? You like you
positioned it as like UMAX for women?
Uh, basically, but what does that mean?
Like why why did you come to this idea?
>> Yeah, so my my co-founder Aaron, he was
in HFZ with UMAX's founder. Um, and they
were killing it, you know, they were
doing really good. It was basically like
jaw lines and all that stuff, like
scores for your facial structures, but
we wanted to do something that's like a
little less toxic in that way. Like we
don't want to rate women on their facial
features. I think there's a difference
between men and women when it comes to
this. Um, and obviously for for men to
glow up, you know, they do the mewing
and the looks maxing, but for women, a
lot of the times it's about skin care
and makeup and and the products that
they use. Um, so it's loosely inspired
definitely by them. Uh, but you know,
with with Glam Up, we wanted to do
something where it's more about makeup
and and the actual products. And do you
feel like you were the first ones to
notice this trend? You're basically
copying the the UMAX uh value prop, but
for a different audience like were you
the first ones to kind of notice the the
gap?
>> I believe so. I think it's also because
we have an advantage just because the
UMAX founder and my and my co-founder
they were in the same cohort together uh
building together and so you know my
co-founder was really familiar with UMAX
very early on during their growth um so
you know we kind of have a competitive
advantage versus you know just
discovering that on Twitter and I I hope
to believe that you know we're the first
one to start this as well. Uh, how like
how are people finding out about this
happen?
>> I was like super happy about this. I
remember I was like I couldn't sleep for
for like an entire night when this
happened and I had to call my mentor at
like 6:00 a.m. and I didn't sleep for
the whole whole night. But uh that was
the time when Glamma reached number
three on the app store. We beat Tinder
and Hinge uh luckily for like a couple
of days. Um but here are some
screenshots from Super Wall. This is
iOS. This is Android. Uh I think well
now I think we have around like two
million downloads but we kind of stopped
working on the app when we hit a million
users. So these are just from like the
leftover distributions that that ramped
up. Um and
we have uh we used to use one link for
attribution links and for referral
codes. Um so as you can tell we have you
know around 1.6 6 million total requests
of people sharing the app, getting their
codes, stuff like that. Um, and when it
comes to distribution, I just went on
Tik Tok and I searched Glamop app and
you can see I'll show you one of the
videos. Um, this doesn't have the audio,
but I'll show you. So, it's a girl
without makeup and then it's a girl with
makeup and it has the Glamour Up
branding and then we do the the like a
screenshot about what the app is about.
So, we did this for across I think 20
different UGC creators. We did faceless
content. This is from years ago, but
when we were killing it, we were getting
millions of views like every single day
from it. Um, and it was pretty sick. And
I remember the first faceless content
that we posted. Uh, it was a slideshow
basically very similar
um, idea. And that one got like 10
million views. This one, like our very
first post got like 10 million views,
which is insane. But as you can see, all
of it is before makeup, after makeup,
glamour branding, and then a screenshot
of it. And you want to know something
really funny? How we did this is
actually we went on Pinterest. We found
a bunch of like pretty girls. We
downloaded another app that can remove
their makeup. So we would go to the app
and we would remove their makeup like 10
times to make them like just like really
plain, you know, something like this.
And then we will enhance their makeup.
So we have this huge contrast. and then
we post on social media and it goes
viral. So these are actually just like
demo demos of our app but these are not
like actual users
um because we don't want to post you
know private information.
>> Right. Right. Okay. So the slide like
the content format is like very simple.
It seems like it's like basically before
and after with this slow sliding screen
transition and then the name of the app
is just like right there. Glam up. Um,
and then it shows the demo of the app
that shows like the personalized makeup
routine, but then on the first couple of
frames of the video, do you have like a
caption or something that kind of acts
as the hook? It's also very funny
because we did this for every single
like we probably had hundreds maybe
almost maybe even thousands of these
posts out and we used the same caption
on the video and the same caption below
the video and the same hashtags and for
some reason this combo just worked and
the same
>> really interesting. Wait, so what what
is the caption? Wait, so yeah, walk me
through the caption and then the like
the onscreen video caption. It's okay.
So, it's literally either two or three
lines. It's never saw myself with the
next line, right? Makeup routine. Crying
face. Crying face. And we've tested this
actually with different different um
hooks and different, you know, lines,
how many lines you can have. We were
like very intricate with it, almost
scientific, and we realized this is the
best one. And then when it comes to the
caption, it's usually almost I will be
unstoppable with the exhausted emoji and
we do like um the hashtags for it. And
then we use like there's
maybe like 10 different audios that we
use. Uh we've tried other audios, it
just doesn't work. It doesn't go viral.
But with those audios with the same
hook, with the same caption, it works
every time.
>> That's so that's so weird. Like I don't
understand. Like the Tik Tok algorithm
is so mysterious sometimes. Like so it
says never saw myself with the right
makeup routine, but then there's a a new
line after the word 'the' and then the
emojis on the third line. So give me an
example of like caption variation that
was that looked very similar but just
didn't perform as well.
>> We tested out the size of the lines as
well. It can't be like super big on the
screen. And it has to be something like
that's very like
>> like Gen Z Instagramly posting like
something. So it has to be
>> like small and it h it like we would
prefer not on the center but somewhere
by the side. Yeah. I think we might have
deleted the ones that didn't work that
well but
>> sure in the search results they're all
the same.
>> They're all the same. They're all the
same. And um we can dive into it a
little later as well but if you take a
look at the comments everyone's asking
for code for code. uh which is the
referral code that we build within the
app. You can see a bunch of people are
doing the templates that you know we
have
>> and that is that is the crazy probably
one of the craziest things about this
app. I want to get into that um in a
minute but first like how did you come
up with this before after slideshow
format in the first place? Like is it uh
were you like paying influencers or did
you just make it yourself? Like how did
you come up with this? So, we have
tested a bunch. Latina makeup slidesh
shows, all that stuff didn't really
work. We tested color theory,
celebrities, all that stuff didn't
really work. Uh, we also tested these
like tutorials, makeup tutorials, didn't
really work. We just kept testing
different formats. And I'm not exactly
sure how we ended up with the before and
after. I think our competitor app
actually helped as well, like a copycat
app that was copying everything that
Glambo was doing. They came up with a
bunch of viral strategies that like, you
know, we honestly got really lucky with
it and we just scaled and made it
better. Um, and then it just blew up for
us.
>> So, you said you had 20 creators. Like,
were you did you hire all those people
from the beginning and just have them
create these these videos? So, across
all four of my apps, I'm the first one
to go viral on on all of them. With
Glamom, I remember I had like three
accounts. My co-founder, he had like
three accounts. We'll warm it up and try
posting. And once we found a viral
strategy, that's when we just scaled
immediately. So, that's when we went to,
you know, hire like I believe at one
point we had like 30 40 creators. This
for Glamop like during that time it's my
first app. It's like a it's a huge scale
for me during that time. Obviously with
Sprout now we have probably over a
thousand creators now but during that
time it was a lot for me. Um but yeah we
just started hiring. We did a training
course for all of them similar to what
uh I can show later for Sprout as well.
It's kind of like a course. We teach
them how to create the account, how to
warm it up, uh how to warm up a brand
new account for like the algorithm, what
exactly to do for the content. So, for
example, all the details I just told you
about, like make the size a bit small,
don't make it center, make it on, like,
you know, all that little details, we
would tell them, we'll come up with a
tutorials for them on how to, you know,
pose and and stuff like that.
>> There's so many people talking about UGC
and creator marketing these days, and
like from the outside, it can seem kind
of almost random and like very almost
like a lottery, but the way that you
talk about it is such a system. It's
like the training like thinking about it
as a talent acquisition game and then
coaching and training them through the
the program um scientifically testing
all this stuff with a thousand creators.
So I want to dive into that entire thing
but first let's let's get into the the
viral system. So like you have this
referral system where people like refer
out to their friends. So yeah, how does
that work? So
this is our entire app design that I can
find from from Figma so far. We have the
welcoming screen. We have the onboarding
screen. Um a lot of people confuse
onboarding and the actual purpose of it.
I think a lot of people think onboarding
is for data analytics. Um and that's
like the the biggest purpose of it. Um I
completely disagree. Obviously, it's
good for tailoring your plans and all
that stuff, but a lot of it is about
priming creators to increase conversion.
So, we would do a lot of like, for
example, beauty goals, skin concerns so
that they think, you know, wow, I really
need this app, you know, and then we'll
tailor like a plan for them and
whatever. So, that will make them, you
know, want to use the app a bit more.
Afterwards, you will see, you know,
different scans that you can do. And
after you choose it, you either pay or
you can refer friends. I don't know why
the code isn't showing up here, but
basically in order to view your results,
you can scan your face. Afterwards, we
hide everything uh behind the payw wall.
So, we blur everything. Um you can
either do view results or invite three
friends. If you click view results, then
we payw wall you. But if you click
invite three friends will bring you to
this like share your invite code and you
can redeem uh you can redeem it. But
basically if you invite three friends to
unlock your results you can get it for
free. You don't have to pay. Um and
obviously for the target customers for
Glamop a lot of them are like younger
kids. So anywhere between like you know
13 to like 25 year olds. Um and you know
they don't want to pay for the app. So
they would copy and paste this code and
share it with their friends. But a lot
of people they actually share it on Tik
Tok which is why you will see you know
the entire comment section with their
referral codes. Um and when we do the
copy and paste we don't just give them
the code we give them a template that
has Glamop inside. So it will be
download Glamob and use my referral
code. Um so that glamop that keyword is
ranking pretty high on Tik Tok. Um, so
whenever people search Glamob, our our
app pops up as well.
>> Wow, that's insane. I didn't even think
about that. Like I like you're Yeah, you
have all these users like commenting
uh you know, use my code and of course
that'll boost your videos, but then it
also like gets your keyword to to rank.
So So like when you tap the search bar
on on Tik Tok, you see all these like
suggested keywords. Did you do you feel
like you showed up in those uh in those
trending?
>> If you search Glam Up right now, it's
all our apps and this is like a random
account that I'm using right now.
>> I see. Oh, so so you're kind of doing it
for um like branded keyword search. So
like if if people are searching for your
actual name of your app, all the people
that commented on these videos, like
those videos will rank at the top. But
obviously I feel like glam up is also
like glam up look like it's a it's a hot
phrase even for people not using right
>> you know that also help but like that's
kind of like a hindsight bias.
>> So it seems like most people ended up
trying to get the three referrals
instead of paying. Do you feel like that
hurt your conversion rate? Obviously it
makes up for it a lot because you're
getting tons of people like sharing and
you get the viral K factor loop but you
did hit a lot of revenue. you got like
more than $600,000 total on this app.
So, do do you have an idea of your
conversion rates?
>> Um, our conversion rate during that time
is low. I I don't think this is the best
app I've built, but this is the first
one. This is the first one I've built
and and I'm like happy about it.
Conversion, I don't think it changed
much because in order to get three of
your friends to download the app, go
through the welcoming and onboarding
pages, and then to do your referral
code, that to be honest takes a long
time. Even for me to convince, you know,
one of my friends to do it in school or
like, you know, if I'm just calling them
for them to do it, you you still get
impatient with it. So, a lot of the
people that ended up sharing the code
actually also ended up converting.
>> So, you're getting the virality without
sacrificing too much conversion rate cuz
people just like it it is kind of hard
to get someone to download an app and
use your code. Did you give any benefit
to the receiver of the code or are they
just inputting the code because their
friend sent it?
>> Because their friend sent it and for
like
>> okay
>> the friend who wants to use it for free,
they have to, you know, share their code
with like three other people. So,
>> and then Okay. Then what was your um
pricing in the playbook? You said like
$3 a week and then you I think you
increased it to like $9 a week. I assume
you had an annual plan as well.
>> I don't think we had an annual plan. I
think it was only weekly and monthly.
>> Oh, I see. Okay. Weekly and monthly. And
then Yeah, it's very it's a very like
low price point. $3 a week and then $9 a
week. Yeah. One of the things that stuck
out in the in the playbook, doc, was
like when you raised your price from
three to 9, like you tripled your price,
it somehow increased your conversion
rate. Like how does that work?
>> I have no idea. But you know what's
something really crazy? the new app that
I built that I launched three months
ago, we just raised the pricing by 20%.
And the conversion also increased. And I
think it's because it depends on the
demand. Maybe like I'm like I'm kind of
just like talking out of my right now,
but like I feel like when you find an
app that you really want to use, your
demand for it is relatively inelastic.
seeing that like maybe seeing the price
higher will bring the perceived value of
the app more cuz maybe they're like,
"Oh, this is so cheap. There's no way,
you know, they can do this or do that."
Maybe that's one way of thinking about
it. But I see it not just from Glam Mob.
I see it from like the the current app
that I'm building as well.
>> So, let me show you this. A lot of app
founders I talk to have a feeling their
app has viral potential but don't want
to be the person brain rot scrolling an
hour a day hunting for formats or worse
burning thousands on creators shooting
videos that just flop. Recently I've
been telling every founder I meet about
Spy Talk. It's basically an AI Tik Tok
viral marketer that I've seen a lot of
top app growth teams use. You just paste
a link to your app and this agent
scrolls hundreds of thousands of Tik
Toks for you. finds the outlier videos
from competitors who've already cracked
the best formats that are driving
installs in the niche of your app. And
then it remixes the hooks, the angles,
and then it makes playbooks so you can
pretty much copy paste virality. And
then it alerts you when it detects new
breakout formats that would also work
for your app. This is the only growth
tool I 100% vouch for on this channel
because there's a ton of Genai content
tools out there, but none of them tell
you what to make. Spy Talk makes sure
you're never in the dark about what's
actually working. Now, I'll put the link
in the description. And do you do that
price increase for the weekly as well
for your new app?
>> Well, for my new app, we are actually
doing only monthly and annual
>> and you increased both by 20%.
>> Increased both by 20% and the conversion
went up. Our revenue per download, you
know, obviously also went up. So, we are
actually testing another 20% increase
now.
>> And then you had a second payw wall,
right? Like there there's the first payw
wall that has the referrals and then did
you have a second payw wall on Glam Up?
>> Um, yeah. So we have the the hard payw
wall and then we have the discounted
payw wall. So once we show them the hard
payw wall, they click out, we
immediately hit them with a 50%
discounted payw wall. So we have the
usual payw wall right here. You know, it
starts from $8.99, $10.99, $12.99. Uh we
only have weekly for for Glamop. And
then we have the discounted one. So once
they click out, we hit them with the 50%
discount. This one is, you know, 4.49,
5.49,649.
And we have an upgrade pay wall where,
you know, you can add to like a higher
tier.
>> So, it's like kind of usage triggered.
So, they get they do scans and then uh
they try to do another scan and then you
that requires a higher plan.
>> Yeah. So, let's say like if you run out
of scans weekly, right? Cuz like we have
the two scans weekly, four scans weekly,
whatever, you want to scan more. Um, and
the reason why you scan more, why you
want to scan more is because we have
different scans, right? We have the
color analysis, we have glow-up guide,
and we have, I believe, another scan as
well. And within the glow-up guide, we
have six different makeup guides that
you can scan your face on. So, there's a
lot of scans that you can try out. Um,
but, you know, we we do kind of like a
limited scan per week. So, that triggers
them to want to do the upgrade payw
wall. Another thing that I noticed was
like the results were blurred. Was that
ever a decision whether to blur the
results or not because like the scan
itself is the value and you want people
to pay to see the results.
>> Yeah, that's a great question. This scan
is completely fake. It's a fake scan.
So, we don't actually get their results
at all. We only run the API after they
pay because we don't want to waste, you
know, the API cost.
>> So, yeah, the the referral system is
very um it's very interesting. Did you
get inspiration from anywhere for that?
Cuz I feel like a lot of people think of
referral systems as K factor where
they're trying to get multiple downloads
from each download that they get, but it
seems like the main benefit was it just
made your content so much more viral.
Have you seen anyone else do that in the
app space?
>> I think a lot of apps actually did it or
at least when I was building it, I was
seeing some apps do that. Uh we do that
for for my second app, Sprout, and my
current app as well.
>> So it does seem like somewhat repeatable
like you've done it you did it with um
Glam Up and then you did it again with
Sprout. Are you doing the same mechanic
for your new apps?
>> Yeah. Also, some some people have found
my Twitter and and read the playbook and
a lot of them actually reached out about
the rating thing, the rating page. I
think it's pretty common. A lot of apps
do it now, but they were telling me that
it helped them a lot when it comes to
the ratings on the app store.
>> The rating. Can you show that screen
too?
>> On boarding, we ask a bunch of
questions. And then we do leave a
rating. Um, and then we don't have the I
rate it like that does not exist. When
you click leave a rating, the pop-up
will show up for you to do that. And
then you can, you know, either rate it
or cancel it. But in order to move on to
the next page, uh, like something called
I rate it will pop up and you have to
click that in order to to move on. So
we're kind of forcing people to lie if
they didn't rate.
>> That is insane. That's crazy. So So
you're not you're not forcing people to
rate you five stars, but you are making
the call to action copywriting like,
"Yes, I rated." And your people are
going to be kind of uncomfortable
tapping a button that says like, "Yes, I
rated it." when they didn't. So, so if
they cancel, if if the if the star
rating popup comes up and then they
decide to not do the rating, does it
basically just stay on this screen and
then they can trigger the the rating
again by clicking the the big pink
button?
>> I'm not sure. I don't I don't think so,
though. I don't think it pops up. Yeah.
Um but like I get your concern. my like
my current co-founder, he's actually
uncomfortable with it. So like for my
newest app right now, we don't have this
like we just have leave a rating and
then you can just continue. Uh but it
still works, you know. I think it's it's
the that you put it out there call to
action for them to rate and you know,
you have a very simple pop up for them
to to go up.
>> It's really No, it's really smart
though. I mean, I feel like people don't
put this much thought into onboardings.
Um like there's just so many like small
nuances in this whole like onboarding
payw wall sequence that I think people
could learn a lot from.
>> Um same thing for you know notification
page as well. Um you can do something
very similar with it.
>> Let's go to the the marketing. So can
you show the stats again for the um I
guess the views cuz I think you got like
a crazy amount of views.
>> That's for Sprout. Um so I can I can
lowkey just like transition into Sprout
does the same onboarding if you want.
>> Um for GlamUp. Did you have any like um
did you have like a a huge marketing
system or is the 100 creators you
started that with like uh Sprout?
>> We started it with Sprout like the the
really big scaling ones I I did it all
with Sprout. Yeah. But for for Glamma we
we also had a course. I don't even think
I can find that course anymore. But it's
like same thing like modules, video
tutorials, all that stuff. Uh but Sprout
we did it way better.
>> Let's anchor Sprout a little bit. So,
how much how much money did Sprout make?
>> I was growing it for the first eight
months and we did 250K MR. So, by
October 2nd, we were doing 250K MR. I
think now they have steadily been
growing at around 200K MR. Like during
the time when I was like growing it a
lot cuz right now I'm just an adviser.
But when I was handling, you know, all
of the UGC's, we were doing 100 million
monthly views. I just talked to, you
know, the Sprout team and they had a
crazy number. last seven days they did
>> wow
>> 400 million views. Yeah. So monthly I
think they're doing around 400 to 500
average monthly. Tik Tok, Instagram,
YouTube shorts.
>> Wow. That's insane. So you so Yeah. So
you were while you were with them you
you're getting like a 100 million of you
views per month. Recently they they're
now getting 400 million views in just
one week which is crazy. But you built
the system that allowed this to happen,
right? like it's 100 creators
>> when when we were scaling a lot. I
remember we have maybe over 200 active
creators at the same time. Uh but we've
already gone through you know probably a
thousand or more than that creators at
that point and I I created this course
for them. Um I do like consulting for
some startups as well. So like I will
you know make a course similar to this
but basically it's like a creator
course. Um, we have onboarded I would
say over a thousand creators onto this
course without any training whatsoever.
And I would say over 50% of the creators
finish this course with no previous
experiences. They go viral within the
first two weeks of starting a brand new
account with us. So that's great. We do,
you know, we have a tight form. We link
this to our CRM system and then
afterwards we have, you know, getting
started warm-up playbook, creating
content, content bank example. I can go
into that more in detail later. And then
we have content policies, account
management, next steps, resources,
bonuses, all that stuff. An example of
the modules I created is it's just me
talking and I edit it in a I try to edit
it in a very engaging way for for
creators to learn and like show them
examples of what we mean by the content
bank how to edit how to introduce the
app in the video so that it can convert
better. Um, and we always have a quiz at
the end of the module as well for all
the creators to take, uh, just to
quality check on the creators and make
sure that, you know, they're actually
finishing the the courses.
>> How many creators like this is very
thorough. Um, and it's it's pretty it's
pretty cool that there's like within two
weeks people are going viral just by
taking the course. Do you have an idea
of the funnel for that? Are most people
actually completing the whole course?
Yeah, most of them because we also
interview them. So like before we
onboard them onto, you know, our UGC
system, we do inbound and outbound uh on
our creators and then we always
interview them beforehand. It can be a
basically like a 15-minute interview. We
want to vive check them. We want to know
if they can do well with their with our
content and we want to know that they're
serious about our campaign. And then
we'll explain, you know, you have to
take this course, take it seriously. We
have quizzes after every module
afterwards you you'll do really great
and we are we have you know we have a
lot of credibility because hundreds of
our creators have gotten viral. So this
is one of our creator she has over 100k
followers right now and this is a sprout
dedicated one. So we taught her how to
create a new account all that stuff. Um
when she just started she was killing it
for us. So let me just show you some of
the views. Okay this is when she just
started. This is literally her first
video and then as you can tell it's
millions and millions and millions of
views
>> uh for every single one of her videos
and she does like one of our skit
content.
>> This is a crazy track record. Every
single video it's like almost every
video is over 100k like most of them are
like multiple 100k to a million views.
>> And so she is really good with our
recruiter call like fake recruiter call
content. This girl, she's another one of
our creators. She has like 60 70k
followers now on this account. She does
a lot of recruiter calls, but she also
goes viral with like talking videos,
like talking heads as well. And we put
all of these content in a content bank.
So, we do a lot of these we do these
like wars over videos that's completely
faceless,
6.7 seconds long. We tested the length
of that video between 5 seconds to 6
seconds to 7 seconds and we found uh 6.7
seconds worked the best for this video.
Um same thing as Glam Up. Like remember
Glam Up I told you we're very scientific
when it comes to like the details
>> caption. Yeah,
>> we did the same thing with this war is
over video as well.
>> That's a really simple video. So that's
a 6.7 second video. It just says war is
over. finally landed my first full-time
job. And then it's just like a
spreadsheet with the drop down. Then you
just like switch to like, oh, accepted.
Like, I got the job.
>> I don't think I can show you the whole
tutorial, but I made a whole tutorial
video on exactly how to film this one
cuz this one probably brought in like
hundreds of millions of views for us and
a lot of conversions. We make all of
these Google sheet templates for them.
We put them in like a Google sheet like
link and then with different templates
that they can use. We teach them how to
position the the angle. It can't be co
completely like 90 degree angle. It has
to be something tilted and then you have
to like like you need to zoom in as at
like certain seconds of the entire
video. You have to zoom in at a certain
pace. You have to it's like super
specific little things. I'm very OCD
about content like this.
>> I can sort of see why. Like the like why
do you think the angle matters? Like my
guess is that it makes it harder to
read. So it makes you kind of like pause
and look at the video longer.
>> I think so. And I think it's more
organic. And then we always do something
that's like first few seconds we're just
showing this. Afterwards we zoom in.
After that we click and we try to do it
a little slow so we so the users can see
but not clearly see all of the options.
And then you click accept it. You zoom
in again. You can see it. Zoom in again.
and it it it zooms back out. So, we we
tested, you know, a bunch of the details
for this one content format.
>> And then how is how is the conversion
happening from this type of video?
>> We are not sure. Um it's always hard to
track attribution when it comes to
certain content formats, but it's been
working well for us.
>> We never fully went into the products
like what is what is uh Prep AI?
>> Let me show you Sprout. This is our
onboarding, but basically it's Tinder
for jobs. You're going to see a bunch of
like jobs that you can get. You can
filter what jobs you want and whenever
you swipe right, we just automatically
apply for you. You can also tap in to
see more like info about the job. We
also have AI tailored resume and cover
letter that you can you can do directly
from our app as well. And the onboarding
is completely almost exactly the same
but better version of Glamour. So, we
have the welcome pages. We added the
sign in uh for Sprout. And then we have,
you know, all these um questions that
prime the users into thinking that they
really need this. Um this is also a nice
little thing that that I learned later
on is you should have these fun fact
pages that aren't questions, but it
shows how valuable the app is. For
example, they ask um we will ask, "Have
you tried other job search apps?" And
right afterwards, we will compare Sprout
with other job search apps. Does that
make sense?
>> Um
>> yeah.
>> Yeah. Same thing here. What is your
goal? Whatever. Whatever. And then the
next page is oh like you can reach that
goal with Sprout way more than without
Sprout. So, we designed these all
together so that you know it it's the
most impactful.
>> And then you have another one here that
says you have great potential to crush
your goal. That's right after what do
you want to accomplish? Make more money,
support family, find a job.
>> Take a look. Leave a rating, you know,
and then enable notification referral
code. It's the same thing from from
Glamour.
>> So, the Tinder for jobs thing is the is
the value prop. I'm noticing like sort
of a pattern. It's kind of like a
there's there's sort of like an end
result that people want for like both of
these apps. Like for Glam Up, it's like
figure out how to, you know, adjust your
makeup to have a glow up or to, you
know, to glam up. And then for Sprout,
it's like get a job. And the onboarding
is walking you through basically problem
and then solution. And then the
improvement that you made with with
Sprout is like instead of just asking
questions about, oh, what are your
problems? you know, what other things
have you tried? You're you're just like
kind of pitching the app like while
they're uh answering the questions
>> basically. Yeah, that's a great way to
put it. Yeah, I'm I'm pitching the app
in the onboarding.
>> And then for the payw wall for this one,
did you make any changes from how you
approached it with ClimUp?
>> We didn't put the discounted payw wall,
but we do weekly/ monthly. We didn't do
annual because we don't think it makes
sense for a job searching app to charge
an annual subscription. that means you
you you will need a year to find a job.
You know what I mean? Um so we have this
weekly monthly and then we do Stripe um
instead of you know the the native app
store.
>> Your Stripe thing looks pretty good
though. Like it it doesn't seem like it
opens the browser. It like it's like
interstitial. It's like still within the
app.
>> I'm pretty sure it's within the app.
>> And then is there any kind of scan
before the payw wall where they're like
kind of anticipating some kind of
result?
>> I don't think so. I think we did
beforehand, but we switched to a hard
pay wall afterwards. I would actually
recommend a lot of users, well a lot of
founders to just completely hard pay
wall right after the onboarding screens
cuz for some reason the conversion is
better for for Sprout and for my newest
app.
>> For Sprout, did you have are there any
screens before this payw wall? So we
have the onboarding, we have the
referral code. Afterwards, you can
upload your resume and this is just an
example resume that I used that I that I
did with like you know like tragic and
you can upload and continue. Afterwards,
you will get into this. So this is like
the first page. Um and because of your
onboarding questions, we know what type
of jobs you're looking for and in what
countries or if it's remote, what
location it is. So, we already have it
preset for you. And then you'll see jobs
that you know maybe you'll want. Uh if
you want to, you can click here for the
filter and you can search you know your
role, you can change the locations,
whatever it is. If you apply, if you
swipe right, then we start uh paywalling
you. And then this is our payw wall. So,
it's like you swipe right and then we
have kind of this welcome screen as
well. And then we we show you the payw
wall.
>> Wow. Okay. So, this is a pretty
different flow. It's still a hard payw
wall, but you're allowing the user to
kind of navigate through the app as if
it's free, free to use. And then as soon
as they hit the point of actual valuable
feature, that's when you paywall um
instead of like paywalling without
letting them kind of like navigate the
app.
>> For Glamob, it's the same thing. So like
for Glamop um after finishing up the
onboarding and everything, you can get
started and we actually bring you to the
homepage and you can swipe to see what
scan you want and then you can actually
click the scan and we will show you what
to do, what not to do for your picture.
You can take a selfie or upload a video.
We will actually scan for you. it will
say analyzing and then we'll go through
this like everything is blurred and then
we payw wall you.
>> It's the same um flow from for these two
apps but I guess it's different from
some of the onboarding flows that I've
seen where the hard payw wall just comes
right after the onboarding without
letting the user navigate through the
app. But I feel like this one feels a
little bit better because when there's a
hard payw wall and you can't navigate
through the app, as a user, I feel like,
what the heck? Like, I can't even like
open the app itself. I have to pay.
Like, I don't even know what's going to
be inside. But with this, you see
exactly what's inside. You can flip
through. And it also kind of targets
um what they actually want. like with
the hard like it you know they're able
to for for Sprout they actually search
for the for the job that they want
whatever that is like software
engineering with glam up it's like
there's different types of scans and
they do the scan that they want the most
and then get paywalled. Um so you're
kind of just like letting people
increase their own intent level before
they get to the payw wall. Did you do
you see like a a conversion rate
increase when you do this? like did you
ever have uh just hard payroll without
letting the user kind of poke around?
>> I totally get like like thank you for
for understanding this perspective. I I
agree and disagree with you because I
think from a user psychology like I
think this is the proper way of doing it
and I did this for my newest app for so
for the stealth app that I'm currently
working on. We also let them, you know,
go into the homepage and we and, you
know, they can they can try kind of some
sort of feature of the app before we
hard before we hard paywall them. But
then we ran a test um of complete hard
payw wall after the onboarding. They
don't even go into this to the app.
Unfortunately, we see a 50% increase in
conversion.
>> Oh wow. Okay. So I was just everything I
said just completely ignore that. It's
the opposite. It's quite the opposite.
That is a very interesting insight
though. Like so you you 50% increase if
you don't allow them to kind of poke
around. Okay, that that was a very that
was like an onboarding paywall master
class. I think um I learned a lot from
that. So we kind of got a little bit
sidetracked. So you you're talking about
like the you know you have hundreds of
creators. You've cycled through people
as they kind of show how um how well
they can perform and then you have this
course where you know a lot of them just
start going viral after 2 weeks of just
you know learning from the course. Is
there any other element of this creator
machine that is you think is
contributing to its success?
>> I feel like the course itself pretty
standard you you know like if anyone's
is experienced in UGC they know what to
do. I think one thing that I feel really
proud of is our content bank. I can't I
can't show the content bank in this
call. Um but I come from like a
entertainment background growing up. My
brother is a director. I have a lot of
friends in film school. So when it comes
to the content bank, I I approach it
from a production perspective. For every
viral format that we have, I have the
content idea, I have the content
details, I have the example videos, I
have maybe audios for it, and then I
have a script. And that script is line
by line what you're supposed to say. And
for each line, I give the emotions that
you're supposed to portray and the shots
that you're supposed to do. emotions.
For example, oh do a sarcastic tone here
or oh roll your eyes here or like you
know like a lot of these like emotional
triggers and I have shots. So like maybe
there's a long shot, a medium shot, a
close-up shot um to switch things
around. So I go really in detail when it
comes to the content strategies to make
sure that you know coupled with the UGC
course that we give them. They know
exactly what to do when it comes to
content.
>> In a way you kind of are like the
playing the role of a director and a
screenwriter a little bit where you're
it's not just the lines. It's like the
stage directions like what what should
your face look like? What's the tone? Um
what's the pacing and being really
specific? I'm not that camera shy, so I
will film example videos to show them
exactly what I mean by like the
different shots, the different emotions.
So, so they can copy off of me.
>> So, when you're finding people who you
want to be creators for your app, you
you said when you do the interview,
you're doing like vibe check and then
you're doing like you want you want to
see like seriousness. Are they are they
actually serious about this? Is there
anything else? Like are you looking for
past experience or people who have made,
you know, viral Tik Toks before? They're
definitely a bonus, but I feel like with
the course, it doesn't really matter.
Like a lot of our viral creators, they
come from no experiences at all. They're
just looking for like an internship.
>> For an internship. So, you're Are you
positioning this as a internship rather
than like a hey, I'll pay you money to
make
>> No. So, we do inbound and outbound. For
inbound, we we actually work with some
big influencers and their Discord chats.
Um, so you know, we'll post an
application form in the Discord chats or
sometimes we will actually just put it
on Handshake and a lot of people,
students on Handshake, they don't really
know much about UGC. They might just
want like a social media internship.
They see our program and they apply and
um, we tell them all about it.
>> The influencer Discord thing seems
smart, kind of weird. Like why
influencer Discords? There are some
influencers that train other creators to
go viral and they host courses and
community calls in their Discord chats,
which is why this is the perfect place,
you know, to get UGC creators because
these are students or whatever it is
that are like already interested in
making content that have been
semi-trained by like an influencer or
something like that.
>> How do you incentivize the the creators?
How do you pay?
>> We pay based on every other UGC program
out there. like we use the same
structure. So, it's flat rate plus
bonuses. Flat rate we usually do, you
can do anywhere between $10 to $30 per
post. Um, and bonuses you can do view
thresholds with a bonus. And usually it
can be like a flat CPM or a decreasing
CPM. A flat CPM would be something 10K
views, $10, 100K views, $100. A million
views, $1,000. Or you can do a
decreasing CPM, which is what we do. So
10k views, maybe $40. 50k views, $50.
100k views, $80. A million views, $800.
Something like that. Usually that works
the best.
>> Okay. So another thing you mentioned is
like Charlie Dio. Like what happened
with her?
>> Yeah. Well, so I got connected to some
big influencer agencies and I was, you
know, looking for Glam Up later on to go
into B2B. So like you know working with
like Sephora or like other beauty brands
out there and makeup brands and like I
was thinking this huge vision of like
you know like what if in 10 years I go
into Sephora and like instead of people
coming up to you to help you out it's
like an iPad and it's glam scanning your
face you know like I had that as a
little dream when I was in college and
then I realized I don't want to do
glammo for like 10 years of my life. Um,
I just unfortunately don't have the
patience for it. Um, and I think the
whole reason why I love consumer apps so
much is because how fast you can iterate
and how fast you can grow. Um, and I
really want to I feel like when I do
find an app where I can sit down for a
couple years and really grow it, I will
I will know it. So, you hit 150 150K a
month with Glam Up and then like 250K a
month with Sprout and then you you're
building two more apps after that,
right? I'm interested to to see the
progression in how you thought about
each one. Like with GlamUp, it was your
first and you kind of copy pasted an app
into a different market, but that was
like the innovation was basically like
market arbitrage kind of. And then with
the second app, you're doing a another
problem solving app, but it seems like
the LTV and like the monetization
potential is higher because if you think
about like what are people willing to
pay for? I imagine your pricing was
higher for Sprout.
>> Pricing is way higher. We have I think
up to $80 a month.
>> $80 a month. Wow. Okay.
>> I think that's a really good question.
Um because I think about why I leave
apps or like why I move on to a new app
and and the reasons for it. I think for
for my first app, Glam Up, I was just
done with it, you know, like I was still
in college. I want to build another app.
I'm not that into makeup or like beauty
anyways. So like it was whatever. Uh I
really wanted to experiment with UGC. So
I wanted an app to really do well with
the the the talking UGC's. So that's
when Sprout came in. But Sprout right
now, we have a team of 10 full-time
people, including the co-founders. And I
think at one point, I just really wanted
to build from a much leaner team. Um,
and I want to do something fun. Like,
I've never gotten I've never applied to
a job out of like college, you know? I
don't really relate to that. I don't I
think that's a pretty boring and painful
like thing to do. and and like hopefully
I never need to go through that. Um, but
I just want to build more fun apps that
get me really excited and like I just
want to learn, you know, about all of
these these stuff. But with the new the
newest apps I'm building, I want to
build it larger than anything I've I've
seen in the consumer app space. I'm very
ambitious when it comes to it. We're,
you know, 3 months in, we're almost at
200k MRR. I want to eventually make it
to bigger and better and more optimized
and just more fun to to build with as
well.
>> 200K in your most recent app already.
That's pretty recent, right? Like how
long have you been working on that one?
>> We launched it in January.
>> January. So, it's been like 3 months or
so. Yeah. Is that the fastest timeline
so far?
>> Well, we're almost at 200K. We're not
there yet. My goal for for this one is
500K by the end of this month. Is there
is there anything that you would want to
tell an app founder that you feel like
most people don't get as advice very
often?
>> Yeah, I think um first principles very
important. I do some consulting calls
sometimes. A lot of the people will come
and be like, "Oh yeah, I saw this on
Twitter. I saw this on Twitter. Uh this
and that." And I'm like, "Okay, but have
you downloaded the apps?" And they
haven't. And the thing is like I I
haven't like I've been building apps for
two years. I never posted anything on
Twitter until, you know, earlier this
year. Um, all of my learnings, Twitter
or X, it's it's only like maybe 10% of
it. Like 90% is actually you downloading
the actual app, like learning from the
onboarding flow by doing it yourself and
testing it on your actual app instead of
just reading about it on X. So, I think
that's something that a lot of people
forget to do because I I do think X
sometimes is like it is a bubble, you
know, everyone's posting crazy numbers
and you just want to listen to them, but
but you have to, you know, be hands-on
with it and be crafty with it. Another
thing, um, is don't be too harsh on
yourself. I think a lot of the times,
like I know some people who are just
building consumer apps just because of
the hype around it, but actually think
about what you want to do and and what
you value and what you find meaningful.
Because a lot of the times what you find
meaningful playing volleyball or
painting a painting is the same thing
that you find meaningful building an
app. And I think if you can find that
little abstract idea that defines who
you are, you can succeed in whatever
industry you you plan to do. So
>> I think that's such good advice. Like
don't just follow Twitter. Like see the
results that people are flexing on
Twitter and then actually download the
app and study it yourself. Instead of
blindly believing it or blindly like
saying, "Oh, that's fake." Just like
actually download the app and see how it
study it. Um but then would you also
apply that to marketing? Like do you
scroll Tik Toks and just like look at
people's marketing?
>> Hours. Hours of it. Yeah. Usually the
ones that are doing the best, they're
not they're not posting anything on
Twitter, you know, like they're they're
keeping it to the you have to find it.
Yeah.
>> This was a great interview. Thank you
for being on the pod.
>> Thank you, Joseph. I'm super excited for
this and thank you for for for
interviewing me.
>> Where where can people find you? Uh they
can find me on X at Made by Cole and I
might do some other stuff later on.
We'll see. And if they're interested um
in the playbook, maybe like you can put
it as a link in bio or something like
that. It's completely free if you guys
want to read the whole thing, you know.
Hopefully it's helpful for you guys.
>> Sounds great. Thanks, Nicole.
>> Bye
>> bye. Something you might not know, most
of the founders I cover on this podcast
are hanging out right now in the
Consumer Club Discord, sharing with each
other what's working now for consumer
apps. So, you can apply to join Consumer
Club if that sounds interesting to you.
And this is the Superwwell podcast. Of
course, you got to check out
superhaul.com. We have more videos on
the channel.